Welcome all of you to my new video.
We have already discussed this in the last two videos.  This
is the Health Elevate Plan of ICICI LBAD.
I have discussed this briefly in a video.
In a video,
I have discussed this entire
policy in depth.
This video is specifically for discussion about
what are the exclusions in the policy
which are built in the policy.
So stay till the end of the video.  You will know
many things about the policy.
For an introduction, my name is
Hitesh Singla.  I am a Certified Chartered
Wealth Manager.  I have been
working in this field for 9-10 years and every time my
videos are related to some product or some
information.
This time we are discussing the product.
So let's start the video.   We will
talk about specified excluded diseases.  First of all,
specified excluded
diseases come under the waiting period.
This will not be covered under the policy for 24 months.  This
means that the diseases that we are discussing now are
not going to be covered by the policy for 24 months.  If you have
just started the policy and if the policy has been
cancelled or you have continuous benefits from
previous policies, then all this will be covered.   Until then, for
some reason the policy has
excluded it from your coverage.
Tumors will come first.
Surgery of any kind for tumors, internal or external
tumors, cysts, nodules, polyps including
breast lumps which are
not malignant and of the minor order,
any
gynecological disorders which are
listed herein.  There will be genital urinary disorders
i.e. stones will be formed
in the urinary system.  Minimal prostatic
hypertrophy occurred.  There was hernia or any
type of hydrocele.
Gastrointestinal problems occurred.  Stones formed
inside the biliary system and hemorrhoids formed inside the intestines.
Had gastric or duodenal ulcers.  So this is not going to cover everything for the
first two years.
ENT surgery of any kind, ear
or tonsils, or if someone has paranasal
sinusitis, all this will not be covered.
Cataract in the eye will not be covered by the policy.
Joint replacement surgeries were done in Ortho and Spine for the first 24 months.  This surgery has to be undertaken or is being undertaken
due to some kind of untoward accident.  Got
gout.   I developed
non-effective arthritis.
Spinal disease and spondylitis of the disc
occurred.  Wherever the
hospitalization is not due to any disease or accident,
except that,
our
waiting period will be applicable everywhere.
Surgery of vacous veins remained in miscellaneous, resulting in vacous
ulcers.  Dialysis became required for
chronic renal failure.  The scale will be the same.
Now let's come to the standard exclusions.
Extended exclusions that are within the policy
These extended exclusions are present within every policy.
So it will
remain almost the same in every policy.  Ah, the first one is
investigation and evaluation.  Any
admission for diagnostic or evaluation purposes will
not be covered.  Where
any diagnostic expense has been incurred
which is not related to the treatment.
Any subsequent
treatment taken after the diagnosis and the
diagnosis was not necessary for that treatment will
not be covered.
Rest Cure Rehabilitation
and Respite Care Any kind of
expense incurred because you went there
for bed rest or did
not receive any treatment will
also not be covered.  Like
custodial care at home.  That means
nursing facility has been provided at home.  A. To
help someone out with breathing,
dressing or moving out, an
assistant or a non-skilled person will
not be paid for such services.  Some
kind of service where the person is terminally ill.
Terminally ill means that they may
die within a few months.  So if
you have admitted them to some respite care centre or rehabilitation centre for their physical, emotional or spiritual needs, then
that will not be covered.
Surgery for obesity will be excluded.
If until then these are the
following conditions which
they have given, four conditions are given here.
If they are following those then obesity will be
covered.  The first is that the surgery should be
advised by a doctor.
Second, the surgical procedure being
conducted should be
supported by clinical protocols.
Third, if the insured person is above 18 years of age, then only
this surgery will be done.  The
fourth point is above the body mass index.
His body mass index should be
above 40.  The first condition or even
if he is above 35 but has some
comorbidities
attached to it like obesity related
cardiomyopathy.  Coronary
heart disease may occur.  Severe sleep
apnea may occur.  Uncontrolled diabetes can lead
to type 2.  If
he is suffering from these comorbidities then he can do it at the
age of 35.
Gender identity change treatment
expenses related to treatment
including surgical management to change the
character of the body to the dose of opposite sex.
So here also the policy will not cover it.
Cosmetic or plastic surgery will
also not be covered by the policy.  This
is also excluded.  Cosmetic surgery is any
way you want to change your appearance.
Someone is trying to do something or someone.
Wants to get reconstruction done.  But if this
treatment is taken due to any accident, burns or cancer.  Where a
part needs to be removed or
poses an immediate health risk,
cosmetic or plastic surgery will be included.
But it will be certified by a medical
practitioner.
Any accident can happen due to someone participating in hazardous or adventure sports.
Like
someone is doing para jumping, rock climbing,
mountaineering, rafting.
So due to all these things, if any
accident occurs due to any activity, then the
company will not bear the hospitalization expenses.  A breach of law is
any kind of treatment in which the
insured person has tried to do something with a breach of law or criminal intent
and due to that some damage has occurred, then the
clause of breach of law will also be applicable there
and the policy will not pay out.
Excluded Providers Expenses incurred
to a treatment with certain medical
practitioners and
hospitals are provided by the company on its website
from time to time where if a
policy holder or an insured
person is admitted, they will
not bear the expenses.  But if the person reaches there in a life
threatening situation or
in case of an accident, then till
he gets
stabilized there, his expenses will be borne by the
policy, but after stabilization,
he will have to be shifted to another hospital.
Maternity treatment which is a
complication of child birth or caesarean
section will not be covered by the policy
until you have taken a maternity plan.
Ectopic pregnancy, as I told you earlier, is
covered as part of IPD.
X is a miscarriage or a lawful
medical termination.  These will
not be a part of the normal base policy but will be a form.  But if
you have taken an optional medical and maternity
benefit then it will be covered.
If the operation is done to correct the refractive error index.
Where the
refractive error is below 7.5 dihedron.  If it is
below 7 diopters then it will
not be covered.  Any unproven
treatment that has
not yet been proven in medical records.   There
is no proof in the documentation or the
effectiveness is also not clear.  The
policy will not cover that either.  Talking about sterility or
infertility, it has also been
excluded from the policy.
Similarly, contraception or sterilization,
any assisted reproductive services
including artificial insemination, if someone
uses advanced reproductive
technologies like IBF, there
are three-four more technologies.  zIFT GIFT
policy does not cover all these.   The
policy will also not cover gestational surrogacy.  It will
also not cover reversal of sterilization.
But here we will remember
that in the policy we had said that the
policy will cover inhospitalization of suicide donor.  So whatever is related to it, if there are
any procedures for artificial insertion, then if they are excluded then
they will be included in the policy.
Similarly, in gestational surrogacy,
if the surrogate mother's part
forms part of her hospitalization, then
it will also be covered.   The
policy will not cover the treatment of alcoholism, drug or substance abuse, i.e. any addictive condition or any other problem caused by it.
Any insured person who tries to get treatment done at Health Hydros,
Nature Clinics, Spas or any such
treatment which does not qualify for hospital or nursing home treatment will
not be eligible
for claim. Any kind of dietary
supplement you are purchasing which can be
purchased without prescription will not be
limited to vitamins or minerals
but has not been prescribed by any medical practitioner.
If you buy it and are using it then the
policy will not cover it either.
Some specific exclusions are there
with the policy itself.  Earlier we
talked about standard exclusions which can be a part of every policy.
We
talk about specific exclusion.
If someone is going to get the circumstance done as per policy ex circumstance, then if
he has to do it due to an accident or
he has to get some medical treatment done somewhere, then the
policy will cover it but otherwise it will be
excluded.  Any screening
or counselling or treatment taken
due to external birth defect or external congenital illness or defect i.e.
any defect that the insured person has since childhood and
any treatment
taken for the same will not be covered by the policy.
Any kind of
prosthetic or corrective devices, any
external devices like clutches, crutches,
wheelchairs,
if there is anything for sleep apnea or some cochlear implants have been
used which have to be
used due to necessary operations, accidents or anything else, then this
policy will not cover it. Any
treatment which is taken outside India,
unless you have taken it under the World Wide Coverage
rider, then it will be
covered.  If there is a nuclear or chemical
biological weapon attack and
any loss is occurring due to it, nuclear
weapons have been
used, any illness is occurring due to emission discharge release of some of its waste or nuclear
fuel,
or
any illness is occurring due to radioactivity, then the policy is
not covering it, if any kind of chemical
attack or weapon attack has taken place, discharge is taking place or
release is taking place.  Some compounds have been
released that have caused illness.  The
policy will not cover that.
If there have been biological attacks in the country,
emissions have been discharged there.
Some biological weapon has been used.
Toxins have been released.  Who is causing
, someone is causing illness or impairing health.  Do
n't purse it.
If there is a war or war like situation, there is
invasion of the country, there are
hostilities, there is a civil war, there is a
rebellion, there is a
revolution going on inside the country, there is an insurrection, there is a
mutiny or the military
power has overtaken the country, the country has been seized or captured,
if any such situation arises then the
coverage of the policy will end there. The
policy is not covering any kind of venereal disease or sexually transmitted disease.
Accept HIV
A person tried to commit suicide.
Tried to self-injure myself,
tried to harm myself.  So
in such a condition, if there is hospitalization then the
policy will not cover that also.  Any
expense related to OPD basis,
if any expense is incurred within OPD basis, the
policy will not cover that also.  Untill
untill you have taken the rider of B Fit.
Treatment: If the treatment is of any
kind in which a treatment or
procedure has been done or any preventive care has been
taken, any diagnostic consultation,
diagnostic you have carried out any
restorative activity or cosmetic services
you have used for such a disease which is
related to the natural path or is related
to the gingiva, then the policy is
not going to cover that also, until and unless
you have to take cover due to an accident.
Acupressure, acupuncture,
magnetic or other therapies.  The
policy will not cover any such type of therapy.
Any element injury
or condition and treatment which is specifically
provided as an exclusion under special conditions in the policy will
not be covered by the policy.
So, this concludes our discussion on the
exclusions part of the ICC LB Health Elevate
Plan.  Hope you
liked the video.  You may have learned some things and understood
what
is not included in the policy.  If you have any query or question,
you can contact me on the given contact number.
If you want to
understand your policy or what
is covered under it, what is not covered,
you can contact me for that also.  Thank
you.